Mahmoud Mohamed

Full-stack Developer



ABOUT ME

I am an experienced Fullstack developer with over 7-year track record in Computer Science. As a web developer, I specialize in building applications from ground zero and seeing them through to the finished product. I'm eager to contribute my skills and experience to a collaborative team environment where I enjoy solving complex problems. I am good with people and at turning technical concepts into easy-to-digest information for people of all levels. When not coding, I enjoy going for a run and reading about the latest technologies. I am very persistent and detail-oriented.

EXPERIENCE

Fullstack Developer

Mesh Firm 2024 - Present Copenhagen, Denmark

As a full-stack developer where I specialize in developing AI applications from inception to completion. In collaboration with the team, I have contributed to the creation of AI applications, starting from ground zero and seeing them through to the finished product. Our focus on leveraging microservices, cloud technology stack, and cutting-edge AI technologies has been instrumental in revamping the product management landscape within Mesh Firm.

Full Stack Engineer

Upwork - Remote

2022 - Present

 Built applications from the ground up using (JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, Express, React), CSS/SCSS (Bootstrap, Tailwind) with custom responsive layouts. Developed new features, provided maintenance, and troubleshooting any issues and bugs. Email: mahmoud292949@gmail.com

Telephone: <u>00201061123564</u>

Website:

https://mahmoud-8.github.io/Portfol

io/

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mahmo

ud-m0hamed/

SKILLS

TypeScript, JavaScript (ES6), AI React.js, ReactNative, Next.js & Node.js Git.GitHub Express.js API MongoDB | Mongoose Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap RestAPI-Design Figma. UI/UX Test-Driven Development Vite, jest, API Testing **Unit & Integration Testing** Agile workflows (pair & mob programming, user stories, scrum), CI/CD

LANGUAGES

English (fluency)

German (intermediate - B1)

Arabic (native)

Technical Support Advisor

Concentrix

2021 - 2022 Cairo, Egypt

 Research and identify solutions to complex technical problems using knowledge base resources and escalation pathways.

IT administrator/ Frontend Developer

AL FAJR FOR TECHNOLOGY 2016 - 2021 Cairo, Egypt

Frontend Developer (2018 - 2021)

- Converting designs into HTML, CSS, and JavaScript code.
- Creating interactive and dynamic elements to improve user experience.
- Using version control systems like Git to manage code changes and collaborate with other developers.

Network Engineer (2016 - 2018)

 Participated in 100+ projects for designing and building internal network infrastructure for a wide range of clients (up to 50 machines in different cities) defining requirements; setting up hardware and software; maintaining, optimizing the performance of the intranets.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Development Program

BIT - Beam Institute of Technology January 2023 - February 2024 Beam Institute of Technology

Degree in computer science

University of Cambridge October 2012 - May 2014 https://www.cam.ac.uk/

PROJECTS

Rent Your Home

- https://rent-vour-home-green.vercel.app/
- https://github.com/Mahmoud-8/Airbnb
- Chat-AI
- https://github.com/Mahmoud-8/Hepha-AI
- https://hepha-ai.vercel.app/
- code-cycle-squad
- https://mahmoud-8.github.io/code-cvcle-squad-/

CERTIFICATIONS

- HiveMQ Certified MQTT Associate(IOT)
- Introduction to Generative AI
- Python for Data Science, AI & Development
- Introduction to Software Engineering
- Introduction to Agile Development and Scrum
- DevOps Essentials
- Introduction to Containers w/ Docker, Kubernetes & OpenShift
- Introduction to Cloud Computing